[Music]
welcome to slow news day i'm steve
poykinan and i'm sarah hall we are here
highlighting artists activists
organizers and agitators who are pushing
back against late stage capitalism here
in the heart of the empire joining us
today we are beyond
grateful and stoked uh is uh
john kiriakou who
has
literally put himself
at the forefront of the fight for truth
about the cia's torture program he was
the first person to go on tv and expose
it in 2007 and for that had his life
torn apart by the government ultimately
spending 30 months in prison and he is
now one of
the most reliable sources for
information
about what our
our cia is is up to and how it operates
in a world of orwellian [__] and
lies uh so
joining please give us a a
a lot of uh a lot of love for john kirk
how are you this morning
i'm doing all right um let's uh let's
jump right in i i talked a little bit uh
about kind of what
your uh
a little bit of your backstory but if
there's if there's anything that you
feel
like is pertinent to that will help
people understand the the situation uh
what what is happening now if there's
anything relatable in in what happened
to you that that would give people a a
little bit more insight into how our our
military and our intelligence community
uh is operating in the middle east uh
and
fbi the intelligence community uh does
on a daily basis
i think we should just automatically
assume that they're lying to us and i
don't say that lightly i'm not saying
that because i'm trying to be funny or
to go over anything look at it this way
the cia told us that they were not
torturing prisoners there was no torture
program that was a lie
the cia said that there was no program
of extraordinary renditions where they
were kidnapping people and taking them
from around the world that was a lie
they said that there was no system of
super prison around the world that was
the lie
it said for example that they had not
broken into
the senate intelligence committee's
computer system that was a lot
i could go on and on and on with the
bottom line being
everything that they tell the american
people has been alive
and the one should we believe
you know when they come out and tell us
for example
that
uh
uh juan guido using using venezuela
when juan white doe is
the legitimately recognized president of
uh
of venezuela because they want him why
should we believe that when they tell us
that the iranians are the greatest
threat based in the united states
why should we believe that
or when they that that the russians are
the bravest threat or the chinese or the
greatest threat or isis is the greatest
threat why should we believe them when
everything else they've told us is built
so i
would recommend i would urge
your viewers
to
do your own research
don't believe anything
unless you've checked it out you know
it's worth spending five ten fifteen
minutes
try to confirm it to repeat whatever it
is the government
that that is that is absolutely correct
uh in in my opinion my opinion and i
think it's a shared one um
uh
at least by a small percentage of people
in america who who aren't persuaded by
the propaganda um
venezuela's new president
says
cia asset to me says part of the team
he's uh didn't go to georgetown
yeah he went to georgetown
yeah
uh a bit given our history in latin
america and the way that we have put cia
assets or employees in in uh
high-level government positions after we
orchestrated a coup i i
i don't understand how the playbook can
be the exact same
every single always
and people don't go hey wait a minute
i've seen this before and it turned out
to be [__] what i
you look at this way look at it this way
this guy is what 35 years old
81 according to a recent call 81 of
venezuela he's never heard of this guy
he's he's not a major political state
nobody knew who the heck he was um
nobody from georgetown
wakes up one morning and declares
himself the president of venezuela i
would say yeah he's probably a cia
he's probably working with cia money i
have no inside information whatsoever
to to indicate that that's the case but
like you where you said this cruiser
and again i just don't see how how
when the pattern is so
repetitive and so specifically
repetitive
why why more people aren't you know
aren't just
really
asses in the streets about this and and
asses in the streets is kind of a
central theme to the show we we don't
think that
voting inside a rigged system in a
duopoly is an effective avenue for
change
especially if we have
11 years left before we hit an
unsustainable point in the the way that
our planet is going to treat us um
so so we you know
we thoroughly encourage people to
get out and and make a noise and shut
[__] down if we can because that's the
only way we're going to get
any kind of of representation in the the
political sphere um
is the problem the propaganda effort
seems to be
especially when it comes to venezuela
more successful than even in the middle
east
and and
people
on the
people in the center people on the right
venezuela's just been a punching bag
historically uh
can you shed any light onto why that may
be
[Music]
invented
relations with
right-wing or federal right
government in
central and south america have been so
much
easier so much smoother than our
relationships have been with various
royal or or quasi-fascist regimes
how many times
in the last
what six
years in the death of of um president
chavez
has the united states
done something to isolate the venezuelan
government and it saw immediate success
you know when people
uh regional countries immediately fall
into the line
the fix is in so we wouldn't see that in
the middle east because
with which we have good relations are
are um untrustworthy of us because of
our history in that region
that's not necessarily the case in latin
america and i think we're the big boys
on the block it might be because you
know the military has been
there are probably a hundred reason
but um
but it shows you how powerful we are
that we can just decide one day we're
going to
unleash chaos
and nobody complains about it while
simultaneously telling people that
meddling in elections is wrong
yeah right i mean out of the one side of
our mouth we said oh my god the russians
gave us donald trump
well on the other side
well we'll give you one white though and
you're gonna thank us for it
uh are we gonna
see boots on the ground in a legitimate
military conflict in venezuela before
the year's up
i don't think so but i think we will see
something in the illegitimate
i think what will
probably
special forces or corporate groups
working closely with collaborative
federal purposes and i think they'll do
more to
harass venezuelans and undermine the
government and if the party
to outright possibly move their property
don't forget that this entire
application is a violation of
international law
there are only three ways in which
we can commit truth to another
three ways that are that are legal under
international law and that is with the
implication of the host government which
clearly is not what happened here
number two is if that government
militarily attacks us clearly
and the third is with the um official
approval of the united nations
but not secretary clinton but the united
nations
and that also happened
yeah it's it's uh it's insane to me and
what's more insane to me is is the uh
the reaction by just regular people like
regular working people who have
no
stake in
the end result of us invading venezuela
for their oil they're just regular
[__] people that are like
oh hey no it's venezuela they deserve to
be kicked and and i think that the
god i think that the efforts that that
our media put into
delegitimizing
any nation that hasn't
fully endorsed our style of of not
necessarily democracy but
uh uh have not been absorbed into the
empire uh how they do it
with
no introspection whatsoever with no no
and these people are [__] road
scholars some of them you know they know
history they know better they just
disseminate the propaganda because
they're getting paid thirty thousand
dollars a day and i don't you had a
crisis of conscience you sat on some
[__] for a couple of years you know what
that's like
you know it it's
for um
do the same thing you know i
participated in a pound especially that
maybe two weeks ago and
it's been a long time since i had smoked
i've spoken and he said something that
it just made it all worthwhile he said
that he had followed my face very
closely and that when i was
um that's what made him decide to go
with his revelations and he said that
without john kiriakou there would not
have been an ed snowden i hope that
more people in cia or nsa
or wherever dwight wherever
to go public
with evidence of government illegality
because if we keep letting the
government get away with it nothing will
ever change
and people like you and and i will be
you know in the in the fringe pattern
frequently and that's just not right
no i i in a sane world we would treat
our whistleblowers the way that we treat
our athletes and we would treat our
athletes like athletes
um
i
i wanted to talk to you a little bit
about iran uh because i
i remember who john bolton is
and i have noticed a pattern over the
last year year and a half
of donald trump's cabinet being
absorbed by
george w bush's friends and his father's
friends and all of those same
for lack of better word deep state or
permanent intelligence state unelected
state
has taken root in donald trump's
administration and we
are illegally in venezuela we're still
bombing all of the same countries we've
been bombing and iran has been
it would be the the feather and john
bolton's gigantic mustache
and he couldn't even get himself
confirmed as ambassador to the united
nations and push not to name him in a
recess appointment
so
why is john bolton the national security
adviser why isn't john bolton secretary
of state
because even in the republican senate
he's still so impossible that he
couldn't get a confirmation uh in
the us senate so you name the national
security adviser
and here you put
this well-known neocon
uh in charge of u.s foreign and military
policy that's exactly what's happening
so first of all i want to say that your
observations are correct
we have seen
in a very short period of time less than
two years a group of
george bush
and a group of
what are called um republican never
trumpers
people who said that they're republicans
they're conservatives and they never
vote for or support donald trump
take you over
the trump administration and it's born
an intelligence policy my john bolton
john
the last person like literally the last
person except for maybe elliot abrams
that's a great point
already
predicted yes
uh elliott
who's who's a proven um
uh war criminal
you
very quickly and very quietly and here
we are where we find ourselves with a
with a neocon foreign policy that's
identical to the george w bush
and yet people are people are saying
trust the plan and people think that he
drained the swamp and people think that
that uh
donald trump walking out and saying we
shouldn't be in syria or afghanistan is
the same thing as we are getting out of
syria in afghanistan and then you see
the report that he spends 67 percent of
his time doing [__] all and people are
like well great because he's not working
but no
john bolton
is working during that time elliot
abrams is working during that time jared
kushner is going around and making deals
that are ultimately just
going to blow up right in his smug
little face
um
but
those people are working when he's not
and that that to me is more dangerous
than an incurious narcissist
trying to
decide whether or not he can
i don't know uh jail people based on
tweets you know
so true this is not what i expected
um
because he was surrounded with the likes
of jared kushner and stephen miller um
but i didn't expect the neocon i i
really didn't i really believed that
that on foreign policy they were so far
apart that they were going to have to
just sit out this administration and
that's not at all
no it's absolutely it
it
it's such a part of the overall pattern
that that i shouldn't be surprised but i
when when they first started coming in
and even brett kavanaugh being nominated
karl rove plucked brett kavanaugh out of
nowhere and gave him a federal
appointment like he is part and parcel
of that crew
and
people's unwillingness to to make that
connection
uh especially
in conservative media uh
especially like trump stalwart defenders
they are not willing to go hey you know
what
all of these people that we just spent
the last eight ten years trashing are
running the show again and and that's
dangerous uh it um
it's a there's a hole in in reporting
that that i find particularly curious
oh i think
i think they're right i think that's
that's one building problem that could
get worse
because you know
trump is a creature
and
he's not a washington insider so he
doesn't really know who the substantive
experts are
in this in this city don't forget for
example that 13
assistant secretaries of state positions
are vacant right now 13
it's impossible to implement foreign
policy when you have no assistance
secretary today to implement it so he
doesn't know
who who the people are at that second or
third tier
were necessary to run the day-to-day
operations of government what he knows
are the people he knows you know the roy
cohens of the world he's dead of course
give you an example of the people that
donald trump surrounds himself with
right um those are the people
and those are the ones were leading
the likes of elliott
i gotta tell you even with donald trump
as president elliott abrams was
literally the last person i
thought would be rehabilitated and
brought into
international
yeah that that to me was
was more of a a nod to
the
uh cynthia mckinney calls them ziocons
yeah
and that was more of a nod to the
ziocons than any other move that that
this administration has made thus far
and uh
i'm
i'm genuinely
disconcerted over the fact that that guy
is not in prison at the moment uh let
alone being in charge of
south american policy in venezuela
um
that's right
that's right that's right well you know
you got to look out for your friends um
i know you don't have that much time
left uh so if we uh
you
when you were employed by the cia you
were in the middle east you were in
afghanistan mostly right
yeah
um
did we have a covert presence operating
in iran at that point
no not that i ever
areas this is not true
the cia is not good
they are they're not as smart they're
not as aggressive as people think they
are and that's why there are so many
many routine
intelligence failures because you have
literally nobody on the ground to report
that to you you have no recruited access
inside the country to report back to you
that's why 911 happened he has literally
zero sources inside of
[Music]
talk about an intelligence failure
you know we talk about these major
intelligence failures being 911 and
pearl harbor and a handful of times in
between i would venture to say that that
we experience intelligence failures all
the time
i mean look at look at the major
look at the major events foreign policy
events of the last generation the cia
missed every single one of them
they missed the fall of the berlin wall
they missed the iran hostage crisis they
missed uh
the transition of power in cuba
they miss everything
and it's because they're just not as
good as they want people to believe they
are
i mean it's either that or they're
helping it along
i i think no because if they were
helping in a bomb
resulting in chaos
that's just dragged the country down
into well we spent 13 trillion dollars
for example on foot
yeah it seems like it would be really
easy to control a population of say 80
percent of the country live paycheck to
paycheck or gofundme was the national
healthcare model or people needed three
jobs to pay bills so the only news they
got was on corporate media who was
selling them the talking points of the
intelligence community in the military
industrial complex but i am a cynical
bastard so
it could just be it could just be me
are you
by by showing you the example of ken
delaney pennsylvania is the nbc news
national security course candidate
formerly with us with the los angeles
times kendallane was taught red-handed
through freedom of information
sending his article
to the cia
for for commons before he sent them even
to his own editor
and the cia was telling him well we want
you to say this uh this way and we don't
want you to say this other thing and
here's some alternative language that we
like better and that's what nbc news was
publishing
what the cia wanted pennsylvania to have
to end it
well that's not democracy
that's not freedom of press
that's the that's the the deep state
dark state whatever corporate
media complex telling americans what
they what they want americans to do yeah
it's state-run media passing is free
market
independent journalism and and
yet you have your show
uh is uh is on sputnik
we're on youtube
you know
uh lee camp is on rt
and
gets treated like a russian asset
you know
uh they kicked ed schultz off at msnbc
and he went to rt you know it uh
chris hedges fire you know left the new
york times because he wouldn't toe the
line on selling the iraq war
and on contact as an rt show
you know it they won't uh
they won't allow
even
the slightest bit of countering the
narrative
that is put out there by
um
you know the government and and the
military industrial complex so it seems
it seems like state-run media to me
i think it is essentially
i mean what's the difference bro
they're just
insane fun
i i couldn't agree with you more i know
you said we had 30 minutes and it's been
30 minutes so uh
uh please guys go check out uh
loud and clear
with brian becker and john kiriyaku
on sputnik radio there's a free app to
download or i can listen right on my my
laptop
uh and then do you have any we're on um
i heard radio itunes spotify and speaker
it's free if you don't want to download
this app
yeah there's a bunch of other good shows
on sputnik too um
and do you have anything else coming up
soon that you would like to plug or
promote
oh on the 21st of february if you happen
to find yourself in salem massachusetts
uh we're going to be at the salem um
keeper series uh talking about exactly
these issues awesome
all right well john thank you so much we
will also meeting you thank you john
we'll pick this up again here soon for
uh part two yeah
look forward to that thanks beautiful
you have a wonderful rest of your day
sir
you too take care all right thank you
thank you so much man
[Music]
do you want to uh
freestyle for a little bit with this
show kind of talk about what we just
[__] absorbed
fill up another 15 minutes
for the episode links
[Music]
we are on record still let's see here
confirm
stop
cancel
split screen
and we are still recordings that was
[__]
seamless
dude that was awesome
uh
wow john kiriyaku
um
you imagine
doing 30 months in federal prison
because you told the truth about a
torture program
yeah
you kind of just got like
financially strangled into it though he
wanted to like fight it with everything
he had but that's absolutely at some
point he said it became like strictly a
consideration for his finances and his
his family he was like one
something million in
i don't know if i i don't know if i
agree with
we're not going to have boots on the
ground in venezuela
like the reporting is starting to come
out that we're already at the border
with venezuela and colombia although
he's right fighting a proxy war with the
colombian army and u.s special forces
seems a lot more
out of the traditional playbook
um
i can't wait for part two he definitely
backed up everything that
you say about the media quite frequently
and
um what i've come to understand too i
can't even stand watching it anymore
so and i did watch a little bit of the
rachel maddow talking about russia
dropping the power while homeless people
are freezing
yeah [__] rachel maddow what was on
the deal with that anyways so okay
she
uh i'm i'm gonna try and find it here
real quick uh but uh
if you guys missed this um
rachel maddow went on
her show
and tried to scare
her listeners into thinking that at any
moment
russia
could hack the power maybe she thought
the fear would keep them warm
russia can hack the power grid
and make them freeze to death and i'm
gonna go ahead oh good there it is
they're
the audio
right
in the dakotas now now what would happen
if russia killed the power in fargo
today
what would happen if all the natural gas
lines that
that service sioux falls just poofed on
the coldest day in recent memory and it
wasn't in our power whether or not to
turn them back on i mean what would you
do if you lost heat
indefinitely as the act of a foreign
power
on the same day the temperature in your
front yard matched the temperature
in antarctica
what would you and your family do
i would take the [__] out of my ears
oh my [__] god
what would you do
if the russians
hacked the power grid i would turn off
the
1983 cinematic classic red
dawn is what i would do i would stop
watching red dawn on a [__] loop the
entire day
while i was doing show prep red dawn red
dog red dog [__] that's why i would
step away from that [__] man that is
absolutely what the [__] are you talking
about with the i'm gonna
tell my who and her listeners are are
not spring chickens man like the average
age is like two years younger than the
average age for a fox news viewer so
it's like 63 65 something like that dude
she is scaring old people for money
scaring old people for money that is
[__] wrong rachel maddow it's wrong
you should be ashamed of yourself but
thirty thousand dollars a day to do your
show will cover up a lot of [__]
shame
how about it's a lot more likely that
our infrastructure is just gonna
collapse because it's so
um taxed to the max
or like pg e is just going to be like
ah that was gnarly rebrand we're out of
here and just leave that roach husk in
the dusk i think that husk is more
likely to blow over and crush us than
the red jack in the power drift
i don't know man vladimir putin is in
the water in flint he is
swear to god i [__] heard it on msnbc
it's [__]
vladimir putin so yeah he was like he
was pretty that felt pretty good to have
him say
uh we're on to the media with the [__]
that they're [__] blowing through the
chodes at people you know they make it
so glaringly obvious that you you have
to
willingly
believe
like it takes more effort to believe
rachel maddow
than it does to hear that [__] and go
are you [__]
kidding me are you you really you just
[__] you
the russians are coming
paid for that how many homeless people
are in that region about 200 000
i think it's like something like two
that she showed on that map probably
about a quarter million i don't know
that's the entire [__] like north
part of the united states i i know that
when they
made a big deal out of 15 homeless
people freezing to death in chicago i
looked up the [__]
stats on how many empty houses there
were and there are almost 2 400 empty
homes
it's not a
an unfixable problem there's just
no will for it i am happy to see that
like the
number one thing trending on twitter
right now is the green new deal which uh
nancy pelosi
vehemently smackdown and called it the
green new dream or whatever
that those people are talking about
nancy pelosi who said that her [__]
super weird clap at the state of the
union was because she really agreed with
what the president was saying and that
she was actually
kissing his ass and not introducing
america to the [__] you clap and i just
want to go on record is saying that
there are at least like a half a dozen
[__] schizophrenic homeless dudes in
santa cruz that clap like that at the
[__] pigeons then the [__]
seagulls that they think are monitoring
their thoughts and nobody is out there
[__] painting pictures of them with
like [__] you know
halos and [__] around them nobody's
[__] putting them on a meme
celebrating their clap and i think it's
[__] [__] man because a they
might be right about the seagulls and b
[Laughter]
nancy pelosi's defense of herself was no
i was agreeing vehemently with donald
trump
huh
she's the most progressive person you
guys could find for speakers huh
remember that trump endorsed her too
first speaker of the house
yeah it's a big club wait a minute
[__]
good luck to us all
[Music]
[Applause]
you